
export default [
  {question: 'What are you working on?', answer: 'FIXD is a device that increases customer retention at the dealership'},
  {question: 'How did you start working on this?', answer: 'We started selling FIXD as a consumer product but realized there was a bigger problem that needed to be addressed.'},
  {question: 'Have you run beta users through this yet? What did you learn from them? What went wrong?', answer: 'Drivers are giving us continuous feedback.  Most just want a tool that they don’t have to regularly use which will alert them when they need to take action.  We were experimenting with distribution strategy early on, and it was awkward.  We would try to catch drivers as they left the dealership while they were getting into their cars, but people were skeptical.  '},
  {question: 'How many users did/do you have?', answer: ''},
  {question: 'Who is your customer/user?', answer: 'Our customer is the service manager inside a dealership service center.  The end user is the driver who receives a FIXD sensor from the dealership.'},
  {question: 'Is there anything that they told you that changed what you were doing?', answer: 'The service manager was paying money for each driver to receive benefits like free towing, but very few drivers knew of them.  We integrated these benefits into FIXD to better educate the drivers and allow us to provide more value for the drivers.'},
  {question: 'What is your next step?', answer: 'Our next step is to sign up an additional 5 dealerships in the metro-Atlanta area.  '},
  {question: 'Are you programmers?', answer: 'Julian’s role is full-time developer, but John and Frederick have some development experience.  Frederick is helping to build the web dashboard, and John is helping on the iOS app.'},
  {question: 'People lie. How do you know this customer actually wants what you are selling?', answer: 'Our objective is to get more customers to visit the dealership more frequently, which aligns perfectly with David’s job description.  '},
  {question: 'So this video led to your startup?', answer: ''},
  {question: 'How many users? What are they doing?', answer: ''},
  {question: 'Why haven’t you gotten the pre-order customers online?', answer: ''},
  {question: 'Why haven’t you done x?', answer: ''},
  {question: 'What do you think will be the most popular part about this?', answer: ''},
  {question: 'Why will people continue to use your product?', answer: ''},
  {question: 'What does this thing you are replacing do?', answer: ''},
  {question: 'What do you actually do?', answer: ''},
  {question: 'So there are existing solutions, is this scalable?', answer: 'For each dealership, we provide a unique dealership code which reskins the FIXD app upon registration.  All we need for new dealership is the color scheme and basic information like phone number, address, etc.  '},
  {question: 'Will the new experience require more effort from the user?', answer: 'The dealership service advisors will need to provide educational material to drivers as they wait for repair, and then help to install the units.  Drivers will need to install the app.  '},
  {question: 'How much does the existing solution cost?', answer: ''},
  {question: 'How did you get those customers?', answer: ''},
  {question: 'Why has no one done this before?', answer: 'OBD-II devices have been tried in the consumer marketplace, but they haven’t reached full-scale adoption.  Partnering with groups who are incentivized to give them out to drivers will greatly accelerate our deployment rate.  '},
  {question: 'How are you going to get the existing customers to adopt your thing?', answer: ''},
  {question: 'How far along are you?', answer: 'We have deployed the app to customers and we are building the web dashboard.  '},
  {question: 'How many events have you done with your first customers?', answer: 'Around 15.  We regularly visit the dealership to get a better understanding of operations and to oversee the distribution of the sensors.  '},
  {question: 'How much do you make per customer?', answer: 'A dealership will order ~2,000 sensors.  This represents a one time payment of $40,000 for the sensors and an annual recurring revenue of $48,000.  '},
  {question: 'How much will you be able to make?', answer: '*he said 1.2T industry and they jumped down his throat, be realistic, do bottom up*'},
  {question: 'Will your team stick at this?', answer: 'Yes.  We are all doing FIXD to learn how to grow a company. Our goal is to experience the entirety of creating a product that people love and growing our company.'},
  {question: 'Who would you hire or how would you add to your team?', answer: 'Another developer who is willing to go and talk to customers in order to build a great product.'},
  {question: 'How did your team meet?', answer: 'Through GT, Fred & John were roommates, John and Julian built a cardboard boat and raced it, and Fred and John were on the same senior design project'},
  {question: 'Who in your team does what?', answer: 'John - automotive & lead the team, Julian - development, Fred - sales'},
  {question: 'Who is “the boss”?', answer: 'John'},
  {question: 'Why will you succeed over others?', answer: 'We will succeed because FIXD notifies the dealership when a driver needs maintenance or repair.  This allows dealerships to reach out to their drivers with problems instead of waiting for the customer to reach out to them.  '},
  {question: 'What do you understand that others don\'t?', answer: 'OBD-II devices selling Direct-to-consumer have not taken off and have proven it isn’t a great business model.  We have learned that dealerships have a huge problem with customer retention in their service department and are willing to pay for and distribute FIXD to better communicate with their customers and increase retention. Our model solves a huge problem for the dealership and gives us an active sales channel.'},
  {question: 'What have you learned so far from working on it? ', answer: 'The service center is what actually keeps the dealership afloat, and these managers are looking for ways to bring customers back to the service center.  They view FIXD as a extremely powerful marketing tool because we know what is wrong with a person’s car.  FIXD allows them to reach out to drivers when they need maintenance, repair, or recall work.  '},
  {question: 'In what ways are you resourceful?', answer: 'We have no money, we have no connections, we are fresh out of school, limited professional experience, and yet through talking to customers - we have built a product that solves a need and have gotten people to pay for it.  For $9, we had a successful Kickstarter campaign, we’ve knocked door-to-door to get our first customers, and we’ve spent ample time in dealerships to learn their problems and how they work. We are resourceful because “NO” to us means find another way.  '},
  {question: 'Would you relocate to Silicon Valley?', answer: 'Yes.'},
  {question: 'What’s the biggest mistake you have made?', answer: 'Not firing a co-founder sooner.  She wasn’t pulling her weight.  '},
  {question: 'What competition do you fear most?', answer: 'We know that the OEMs will be developing this in the future.  It will be several years before their telematics solution is fully flushed out. However, their solutions will be focused on the relationship between OEM & driver, not the dealership and the driver. '},
  {question: 'Who might become competitors?', answer: 'Any of the large dealership management systems and software providers like R&R, X-Time, DealerTrak.  These companies range from online scheduling to marketing, but we have no IP to stop them.  Also, our success could entice other B2C OBD-II companies to change business models.'},
  {question: 'Who are your competitors?', answer: 'Currently mail flyers, emails, call centers.  '},
  {question: 'What do they use to solve that problem right now?', answer: 'Emails, mail flyers, call centers - trying to catch customers when there is a problem as opposed to advertising when there is an actual problem'},
  {question: 'What, exactly, makes you different from existing options? ', answer: 'Other options rely on the customer to choose the dealership when they have problems.  FIXD allows dealerships to reach out to their drivers with problems instead of waiting for the customer to reach out to them.  '},
  {question: 'What is your burn rate?', answer: '~$2,500/month'},
  {question: 'How long can you go before funding?', answer: 'We can last for another 6 months at our current rate.'},
  {question: 'Have you raised funding?', answer: 'No.  Bootstrapped.'},
  {question: 'How much money could you make per year?', answer: 'If implemented in every dealership, 3000*17000*2*12=$1.2B ARR PLUS 20*3000*17000= $1.02B 3x times this opportunity for auto service and parts chains + independent market, in USA alone.  '},
  {question: 'How will you make money?', answer: 'Charge dealerships $20 for each sensor given to customers and then $2/user/month'},
  {question: 'How much does customer acquisition cost?', answer: 'We are allocating about 4 hours per customer for sales and training. It will also take about 5 hours per new customer to spin up a new version of the app.  The cost to bring on a new customer comes to ~$800'},
  {question: 'How are you meeting customers?', answer: 'Dealerships - in person visits Drivers - giving out units at dealerships and talking. Future plan is tradeshows, dealership sales channels, and ...'},
  {question: 'How many users are paying?', answer: 'All/both'},
  {question: 'What will you do if we don\'t fund you? ', answer: 'Improving the product, selling to more dealerships, and making sure we hit our KPIs of …...'},
  {question: 'Who is your user?', answer: 'dealership'},
  {question: 'What problem are you helping them with?', answer: 'Customer retention & targeted marketing'},
  {question: 'Why is this a problem for them?', answer: 'After 3 years, 70% of customers have left the dealership.  This number rises to 92% for cars older than 6 years.  Customers represent $800/year in revenue.  The dealership is missing out on $9MM annually on revenue from service center customers.  '},
  {question: 'What do they like about this solution?', answer: 'Its cheap - occasionally catch customers when they need work done'},
  {question: 'What do they not like about this solution?', answer: 'People perceive these communications as spam - 95% of mailers/emails are ignored.  Blind advertising.'},
  {question: 'How do you know customers need what you’re making?', answer: 'They were willing to pay before we had it built, and we know it solves a large problem. 70% customers drop off after 3 years, customers represent $800/year in revenue, costing a dealership ~$9M annually.  '},
  {question: 'What do they wish that solution could do for them?', answer: 'Bring in more customers to the service center.'},
  {question: 'How is your solution better?', answer: 'We let the service center be the first to communicate and advertise to the customer the instant a problem is detected'},
  {question: 'Why would they switch to your solution?', answer: 'Better relationship with customer, more tailored advertising, automated process saves them time & makes life easier.  They can offer to fix actual problems rather than guessing.  '},
  {question: 'What do you know about these users that no one else knows?', answer: 'Dealerships - dealerships want to deliver a consistent experience for customers, but a high employee turnover makes that very difficult Drivers - We have seen what makes drivers REALLY mad!  These include surprises in pricing, disagreements in what work the customer authorized, and conveying the status of vehicle repair.  '},
  {question: 'How many of these users are there?', answer: 'Dealerships - 17,000, Annual drivers- ?'},
  {question: 'How many do you have now?', answer: '2 dealerships, 225 drivers'},
  {question: 'How did you get them?', answer: 'Went in person and pitched'},
  {question: 'What’s the conversion rate?', answer: '50%...small sample size'},
  {question: 'How will you get more?', answer: 'Short term - we will go in person Long term - sell into dealership networks, trade shows, independent reps who sell products into dealership'},
  {question: 'How many more will you have in 3 months?', answer: 'Our goal is to have 15 dealerships signed on by end of summer'},
  {question: 'What do these users currently pay to have this problem solved?', answer: 'Average about $1/flyer and then the pay for a full-time call center employee'},
  {question: 'Would they be willing to pay more for something better?', answer: 'Yes'},
  {question: 'Why are these users good users to try to solve problems for?', answer: 'They aren’t marketers and don’t like advertising.  They fix cars.  They want to try something to automate the process.'},
  {question: 'What other kinds of users could you go after once you get all these users using your software?', answer: 'Parts chains, service chains, independent repair chains. Model applies to all.  '},
  {question: 'What makes new users try you?', answer: 'Service managers can ensure that customers are receiving a consistent experience with the dealership and drivers are given the product for free.  '},
  {question: 'Why did you pick this idea to work on?', answer: 'John is car guy, FIXD started to help drivers understand cars.  We asked dealerships to sell FIXD, but they wanted all the data.  We learned they have a problem with retention, so we changed our business model to make the dealership our customer.  '},
  {question: 'Why do the reluctant users hold back?', answer: 'They want to see it deployed b/c they weren’t sure if it would work.  Initial concerns over safety, liability  '},
  {question: 'What problems/hurdles are you anticipating?', answer: 'We know some customers will want additional integrations for their dealerships, but that will take too much time on cust by cust basis.  -Security concerns as we grow, hackers. -We need to find a way to properly incentivize service advisors to distribute FIXD to drivers'},
  {question: 'How will you overcome them?', answer: 'Listen for most common requests and look at feasibility, then execute if it makes sense for us.  Security Things.  Testing incentives and distribution for FIXD.  Finding way to help CSI scores.'},
  {question: 'What are the top things users want?', answer: 'Dealerships want more more customers to visit more frequently. They have asked for in-app payment and approval of services, a timeline to see progress of vehicle repair, and an in-app history of vehicle repairs.'},
  {question: 'What is your user growth rate?', answer: 'Small sample size, but ____'},
  {question: 'What has surprised you about user behaviour?', answer: 'We originally intended for FIXD to be given to drivers in the maintenance department, but the service manager wants this to be given to individuals buying used cars as well.  We learned that they have difficulty in getting off-brand used vehicles back for service, and he believes this would be a way to encourage them to come back.  '},
  {question: 'What are the key things about your field that outsiders don\'t understand? What do you understand that others don\'t?', answer: 'The service center is the most profitable part of a dealership, and retaining customers is one of the dealership’s top priorities.  Their ability to get customers to come back for service means life or death.'},
  {question: 'How are you understanding customer needs?', answer: 'Dealers - going to dealership, shadowing positions and interactions, talking to employees and manager Drivers - talking to random individuals who go to the dealership'},
  {question: 'How will customers and/or users find out about you?', answer: 'In person visits, trade shows, and a well connected industry'},
  {question: 'What is your distribution strategy?', answer: 'Customers order sensors each month.  Drivers are given the sensor and informational material to read over while they wait on their vehicle.  The Service Advisor then helps the driver install the sensor (~1 minute) as they leave the dealership.'},
  {question: 'What’s the funniest thing that has happened to you?', answer: 'Pep boys - flying up story'},
  {question: 'Tell us something surprising you have done?', answer: ''},
  {question: 'What’s the worst thing that has happened?', answer: 'We had a $750K deal with Pep Boys before they were bought out.  We invested a lot of time and energy into that for it to not pay out.  Learned a lot about enterprise sales in process.'},
  {question: 'What’s an impressive thing you have done?', answer: ''},
  {question: 'What systems have you hacked?', answer: ''},
  {question: 'Where is the rocket science here?', answer: ''},
  {question: 'What is the next step with the product evolution?', answer: 'We have the app built, but now we are building the dashboard for the service dept. To automate campaigns.'},
  {question: 'What obstacles will you face and how will you overcome them?', answer: '1 - technical challenges: network of people to help at GT 2 - industry connections: advisors through ATDC and connections made in ATL 3 - sales: finding a way to scales sales into dealerships'},
  {question: 'How does your product work in more detail?', answer: 'The FIXD app connects to the FIXD sensor via Bluetooth when we detect that you are in your vehicle.  The sensor acts as a pipe which sends vehicle data to our central server, where we are then able to translate it and make it meaningful for the driver.  This information is also relayed to the dealership so proper action can be taken.'},
  {question: 'Six months from now, what’s going to be your biggest problem?', answer: 'With our current team, our biggest problem is going to be getting our foot in the doors of dealerships.  We need a way to accelerate the sales process.'},
  {question: 'What’s new about what you make?', answer: 'Current methods used by dealership service centers for outreach are analogous to polling in comp. Science.  Dealerships check with the driver periodically, hoping to catch them when there’s a problem.  FIXD is like event-based programming, where the dealership can act immediately when a driver has a problem. FIXD allows dealerships to reach out to customers when they need maintenance and repairs instead of waiting for the customer to reach out to them.'},
  {question: 'Why isn’t someone already doing this?', answer: 'Other OBD-II companies made a bet that they could create a marketplace for service by selling directly to consumer.  They were wrong.  '},
  {question: 'How is your product different?', answer: ''},
  {question: 'Are you open to changing your idea?', answer: 'Yes, we have already made important changes, and we see a direction that we are moving towards.'}
];
